TANVIR AHMED

CERTIFIED PROFESSIONAL LEVEL 2 CRICKET COACH

+880 1716-479663 · tanvirnuhun@gmail.com · @coachtanvirahmed Parliament View (BTI), Block -A, Lalmatia, Mohammadpur, Dhaka-1207



📊 <u>coachtanvirahmed</u> 🤀 <u>coachtanvirahmed.com</u> 🔀 <u>tanvir@coachtanvirahmed.com</u>

SUMMARY

an accomplished cricket coach with extensive experience in player development, coaching, and administration. As the founder of Amirun Srity Cricket Academy, he has nurtured talent and overseen multiple cricket teams and businesses, showcasing his commitment to advancing the sport. Tanvir's leadership within the Bangladesh Cricket Board underscores his dedication to cricket's strategic development and promotion. With a passion for excellence and a proven track record, Tanvir is a valuable asset to the cricketing community.

STRENGTHS AND EXPERTISE

- P&L Management
- **Business Development**
- Strategic Planning
- Financial Reporting
- Negotiation Skills
- Client Relationship Management
- Team Leadership
- Communication
- Operations Management

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

BANGLADESH CRICKET BOARD (BCB)

COUNCILOR

2017 - Present

- Coordinated the Dhaka Third Division Qualifying Cricket League & Third Division Cricket League under (CCDM) Cricket Committee of Dhaka Metropolitan, Bangladesh Cricket Board(BCB) Since 2017.
- Member Game Development, Bangladesh Cricket Board(BCB)
- Coordinated the BCB Academy Cup under Game Development, Bangladesh Cricket Board since 2019.

AMIRUN SRITY CRICKET ACADEMY TEAM

HEAD COACH

2015 - Present

- Coahing the entire team
- Guiding the assistant coaches

SUNNYDALE SCHOOL

HEAD COACH (CRICKET)

2017 - Present

- Coaching the entire team
- Player Selection Campaign
- Player Grooming
- Solving Sports Technical Issues

WHEATON INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL

SPORTS Coach (CRICKET)

2024 - Present

- Coaching the entire team

- Player Selection Campaign Player Grooming Solving Sports Technical Issues

AVERROES INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL

SPORTS INSTRUCTOR/ COACH

2024 - Present

- Coaching the entire team

- Player Selection Campaign Player Grooming Solving Sports Technical Issues

DHAKA METRO(BCB)

ASSISTANT COACH U-14

2017 - 2018

- Assist Head Coach in planning and executing
- Coordinate Team Strategies
- Mentor Junior Coaches
- handle Administrative Tasks

FEAR FIGHTERS SPORTING CLUB

HEAD COACH - SECOND DIVISION TEAM 2019 - 2020

PURBACHAL SPORTING CLUB

HEAD COACH - SECOND DIVISION TEAM 2017 - 2020

MOHAMMEDPUR CRICKET CLUB

HEAD COACH - FIRST DIVISION TEAM 2017 - 2020

LALMATIA HOUSING SOCIETY SCHOOL & COLLEGE

COACH 2017 - 2021

PERSONAL PROJECT

AMIRUN SRITY CRICKET ACADEMY

CRICKET COACHING ACADEMY

Founder, Owner & Head Coach 2012 - Present

- Plan and execute all training sessions.
- Maintain equipment and facilities. Stay updated on coaching methodologies.
- Mentor assistant coaches and players.
- Handle admin duties effectively.

DHAKA ASSETS

FIRST DIVISION CRICKET CLUB

2017 - Present Founder, Owner, & Head Coach

- Plan and execute training.
- Develop and implement team strategies for matches. Provide comprehensive feedback to players.
- Scout and recruit talented players.
- Mentor assistant coach
- Handle admin duties effictively

AZIM CRICKET CLUB

FIRST DIVISION CRICKET CLUB

Founder, Owner, & Head Coach 2018 - Present

- Planning & executing trainings
- Developing Strategies
- Mentoring assistant coaches Handle admin duties efficiently

SPORTS WING

SECOND DIVISION CRICKET CLUB

Founder, Owner & Head Coach 2019 - Present

- Planning & executing trainings Developing Strategies
- Mentoring assistant coaches
- Handle admin duties efficiently

CITY LINK

TOURISM TRANSPORTATION SERVICES

Founder & Owner 2019 - Present

- Maintain corporate communications
- Handle admin duties

PERSONAL GAMEPLAY EXPERIENCE

Nabin Shangha Club 2nd Division	2008-2013
Kakrail Boys Club 2nd Division	2009 - 2011
Lalbagh Anwar Club 3rd Division	2007 - 2008
Azad Boys Club 1st Division	2006 -2007
PWD Club 2nd Division	2005 -2006
Young Owins Club 2nd Division	2002 -2005
Bangladesh Boyz Club 1st Division	2003 - 2004
Udity Club 2nd Divsion	2001 - 2002

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

ANOWARA GROUP CRICKET TEAM

COACH 2014 - 2015

NOBIN SHANGHA CRICKET ACADERMY

COACH 2008 - 2009

RAMIJUDDIN COLLEGE TEAM

COACH 2007 - 2009

SHYAMOLY CRICKET CLUB

COACH 2007 - 2008

EDUCATION

MASTER OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION Incomplete

MAJOR IN MANAGEMENT

Premier University Bangladesh

Dhaka, Bangladesh

BACHELOR OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION 2002 - 2005

MAJOR IN MANAGEMENT

Premier University Bangladesh

Dhaka, Bangladesh

HIGHER SECONDARY CERTIFICATE 2000 - 2001

BUSINESS GROUP

Bangladesh Open University

Dhaka, Bangladesh

SECONDARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE 1998 - 1999

BUSINESS GROUP

Bangladesh Open University

Dhaka, Bangladesh

COACHING ACHIEVEMENTS

Head Coach Sunnydale School Cricket Team Inter-School Tournament 2023 Champion	2023
Head Coach Sports Wing Dhaka Third Division Cricket League – 2022 -23 Champion	2022-2023
Head Coach Sunnydale School Cricket Team Inter-School Tournament 2022 Champion	2022
Head Coach Amirun Srity Cricket Academy Dhaka Third Division Cricket League 2021-2022 Champion	2021-2022
Head Coach Purbachal Sporting Club Promoted from 2nd division to 1st division.	2019 - 2020
Coach Nakhalpara Cricketers Dhaka Third Division Qualifying Cricket League 2019 -2020 Champion	2019-2020
Head Coach Amirun Srity Cricket Academy Team at BCB Academy Cup 2019 Champion (Whole Bangladesh)	2019
Head Coach Sunnydale School Cricket Team Inter-School Tournament 2019 Champion	2019
Head Coach Purbachal Sporting Club Promoted from 3rd division to 2nd division	2018-2019
Head Coach Purbachal Sporting Club Champion Dhaka 3rd Division Cricket League 2018 -2019 Champion	2018-2019
Head Coach Azim Cricket Club Dhaka Second Division Cricket League 2018 -2019 Champion	2018-2019
Head Coach Sunnydale School Cricket Team Inter-School Tournament 2018 Runners-up	2018
Head Coach Dhaka Assets Dhaka 2nd Division Cricket League 2017-2018 Champion	2017-2018
Head Coach Fear Fighters Dhaka 2nd Division Cricket League 2017 -2018 Runners-up	2017-2018
Head Coach Dhrubo Sporting Club Dhaka 3rd Division Cricket League 2017 -2018 Champion	2017-2018
Head Coach Sunnydale School Cricket Team Inter-School Tournament 2017 Champion	2017
Head Coach Mohammedpur Cricket Club Dhaka 2nd Division Cricket League 2016-2017 Runners-Up	2016-2017
Head Coach Purbachal Sporting Club Dhaka 3rd Division Cricket League 2016-2017 Champion	2016-2017
Head Coach Amirun Srity Cricket Academy Shahid Gulzar Cricket Tournament 2016 Champion	2016
Coach Anowara Group at Indoor Cricket Tournament 2015 Earned the title.	2015
Coach Ramijuddin College Team at the Inter College Cricket Championship 2009 Earned the title.	2009

CERTIFICATIONS

Level "2" Cricket Coach | Bangladesh Cricket Board | COURSE

Level "1" Cricket Coach | Bangladesh Cricket Board | COURSE

Level "A" Cricket Coach | Bangladesh Cricket Board | COURSE

Pace Bowling Course | BAC International Study Center and EDEXCEL, UK | WORKSHOP

Batting Course | BAC International Study Center and EDEXCEL, UK | WORKSHOP

Fitness Course | BAC International Study Center and EDEXCEL. UK | WORKSHOP

Wicket Keeping Course | BAC International Study Center and EDEXCEL, UK | WORKSHOP

CORPORATE COLLABORATIONS

- Prime Bank PLC
- Brac Bank PLCCity bank PLC
- IFIC Bank PLC
- HSBC Bank
- Standard Chartered Bank
- Pubali Bank PLC
- Beximco Group
- Square Group
- Jahangir Nagar University
- Atom Engineering Innovative Solutions
- BKash

- Tiger IT
- SSLCOMMERZ
- Dekko Accessories Limited
- Networld Technology Limited
- LifeSpring Consultancy Limited
- The Ibn Sina Pharmaceutical Industry PLC
- Jamuna Bank PLC
- X10 Technology
- CodeKnight Solution Limited

SOFT SKILLS

TECHNOLOGICAL

Office: Microsoft Office 365, Google Suite & Workspace

Feb 2018

May 2015

Dec 2014

Operating System: macOS, Windows.

LANGUAGE

English, Bangla, and Hindi